mediaringtalk.com 2010-05-15

# Welcome to MediaRing Talk

---|---  
|  |   
---|---  
|   |  | 

|    
---  
|  | 

MediaRing® Ltd, organized under the Laws of the Republic of Singapore, and its affiliates, including but not limited to MediaRing.com, Inc. a corporation organized under the Laws of California, USA (hereinafter referred to as "MediaRing") acknowledge the importance of protecting the privacy of personal information provided by our users. This Privacy Policy describes our information collection and use practices and the privacy of information we receive from you. If we change our Privacy Policy, we will post the changes on this page, and may place notices on other pages of the web site so that you may be aware of the change. Your continued use of our services will signify your consent to our use of your information. If you do not agree, stop use of the website and/or services and deregister as a user of our services. 

MediaRing does not target services to individuals less than age 13. Individuals less than 13 years of age are not eligible to register or initiate our services. Please register after you have reached age 13.   
  
---  
   
INFORMATION COLLECTED  
**When visiting our website you may provide us with the following types of information: personal and demographic information you knowingly choose to disclose that is collected on an individual basis ("Personally Identifiable Information") and Web site use information collected on an aggregate basis as you use our service or browse our Web site.**  
**1\. PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION.**  
  
**Registration Information**. In order to provide service to you, MediaRing collects your name, email address, gender, country and date of birth, among other information. If you choose not to register or provide such personal information, you can still visit most of MediaRing's web site. However, you will not be able to initiate our services, including the Mediaring Talk client application.

 **Demographic Information**. MediaRing collects demographic information from you, including but not limited to gender and your date of birth. This information helps us tailor messages and services to your interests and provide you with a safe, efficient and enjoyable experience.

The registration information and certain demographic information is personally identifiable information ("PII"). We never sell or rent PII to third parties. We do not disclose your PII to third persons or use your PII for any purpose other than as identified above, except 

  1. your IP address always accompanies your chat or telephone call or SMS message,
  2. as required by law, valid subpoena, or to comply with law or enforce a legal right, or
  3. if you authorize us to disclose your PII, including, but not limited to your continued use of our service after this Privacy Policy has already been made available for your review.

We use PII to provide you with 

  1. information about MediaRing products, services, and updates, and 
  2. other information that may be of interest to you.

We provide such information to you by email or through digital advertisements on the MediaRing Talk client application. If you would like to stop receiving any or all of this information, you may do so at any time by giving us an email to [**cs@mediaringtalk.com**](mailto:cs@mediaringtalk.com). However, you cannot opt out of emails that involve information on your account status or MediaRing Talk® service-related matters, or out of advertisements on the client application.

If you choose to correspond with us through email, we may retain the content of your email messages together with your email address and our responses.

 **Credit Card Information**. If you purchase a MediaRing premium service and pay using a credit card, we collect your credit card information, which is used for processing payments only and not for any other purpose. We send all credit card transaction information to a third-party intermediary for authorization and authentication, and of course send charge information to your credit card issuer.

 **Third Party Information**. If you originate a telephone call or send an email message or SMS message to a third party, you give us the third party's contact information, such as telephone number or email address or SMS message address. We complete the call and/or send the email or SMS message but do not retain that person's information to contact them later to solicit them to join our service or for other purposes. MediaRing has a program (“Tell-a-Friend”) where we solicit the names and addresses of people who may be interested in our services. We use the information received under that program to send – at your request -- a potential user an email invitation to join our service.

 **Phone Conversations**. MediaRing does not record, listen to, or disclose your conversations or communications when using the services offered hereunder, unless required to do so by valid court order or as otherwise required by law. MediaRing does maintain a log of your calls and SMS messages – see “Customer Proprietary Network Information” below.

 **Text Chat Records**. MediaRing Talk offers each person who signs up for the services the capability of keeping a text record of his or her text chat session. You can configure your computer to "save" your text chat session by following the instructions in the FAQ guide on [**www.mediaringtalk.com**](http://www.mediaringtalk.com/). Likewise, the person you are text chatting with can also elect to keep a record of the session. However, one person in a text chat session cannot ascertain whether the other person in the session is keeping a record of the text chat session. MediaRing does not keep a record of the content of your chat session, unless otherwise required to do so by valid court order or as otherwise required by law, but MediaRing’s records do show whether a chat session took place.

When you send a SMS message or if someone replies to your SMS message, a copy of the message is never stored on our servers. A transaction record will be saved for billing purposes. Copy of sent message and received messages will be stored on your computer and the same applies to the recipient (computer/mobile phone). Incoming and outgoing messages may stay on our servers during the transit time (waiting to be delivered)  
  
**2\. AGGREGATE INFORMATION**  
  
MediaRing collects aggregate information about use of our web site, using surveys, cookies, and data-mining technologies. We track such information as the number of visitors, duration of visits, how our site is navigated, and the kinds of browsers that visit our site. Information on general web site usage is aggregate information rather than PII.

We also collect information on use of our services. While you are making a call or having a chat session or sending or receiving an SMS message, we track the duration of the call and of the chat session and of the SMS message and keep records of that. We also keep information on where a call originates and where it terminates, and maintain the same information for SMS messages. We do this for billing purposes and for recordkeeping as required by law and for our internal planning requirements.

We use aggregate information to understand our business better so we can upgrade our infrastructure in accordance with user needs. We may disclose aggregate information to third parties, but a recipient of aggregate information will not be able to trace it back to any individual user or a user’s PII.  
  
**3\. PROFILES**  
  
One of the ways we pay for the services we provide is by serving advertisements while you use our services. We use all of the information available to us to create profiles of our user base. Some of the information helps create a profile of an individual user, while other information helps create a profile of our users in aggregate. We may provide this profile information to advertisers, but not as PII, and only in aggregate terms. For example, we may inform advertisers that we have a certain number of registered users who have an interest in a topic and are interested in receiving information about the topic. This helps to tailor information from advertisers to your interests.  
  
**4\. CUSTOMER PROPRIETARY NETWORK INFORMATION ("CPNI")**  
  
MediaRing maintains a record of your sign-ins to the MediaRing Talk service and of calls each subscriber has made, including call origination number, call termination number, duration and time of call, and account balance, among other information, such as a log of text chat sessions and of SMS messages sent and received. MediaRing does not disclose such CPNI of a subscriber to third parties except (a) as otherwise required by law or to enforce its rights, or (b) to accomplish a task on MediaRing’s behalf, in which case disclosure is subject to strict obligations of confidentiality.  
  
WHO COLLECTS INFORMATION?  
  
MediaRing collects registration information and demographic information from you, as described above. MediaRing also collects aggregate information and CPNI. MediaRing holds information collected from you in servers and other computer systems owned and operated by MediaRing and/or its subsidiaries in the United States and Singapore and various other locations. By registering, you consent to MediaRing’s transfer of your PII and aggregate information from your country to such locations.

 **Cookies**. Our web site sets "cookies" to help deliver content specific to your interests, to customize our web site for you, and to save your password and member name so that you don't have to enter it each time you visit. Cookies are text files that are stored on your personal computer (“PC”) and that allow web sites to identify you. Cookies help us target advertising and other information to your interests and prevent duplication of ads served to your browser. If you do not want cookies to be stored on your PC, web browsers such as Netscape and Internet Explorer provide the option to disable them. Please bear in mind that some personalized services on our web site may be impacted if you choose to disable cookies.

 **Third Parties**. If you click on an advertisement on the client application, third party advertising agencies or ad networks may keep a record of that and of your IP address, and may use that information to send you additional targeted ads if you go to a third party website with which the ad agency or ad network has a business relationship and click on an ad. Such third party websites are not under the control of MediaRing and it is possible that these websites will have privacy policies substantially different from this one. MediaRing’s Privacy Policy only applies to PII that is collected and retained through your use of the Talk client application or use of MediaRing’s website, MediaRing products and/or your relationship with MediaRing. MediaRing has no responsibility and accepts no liability for these third party websites.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads through MediaRing Talk. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [**click here**](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).  
  
SHARING INFORMATION WITH THIRD PARTIES  
  
We may enter into alliances, partnerships or other business arrangements with third parties who may be given access to personal information including your name, address, telephone number and email for purposes of providing you information regarding products and services that we think will be of interest to you. As our customer we will notify you when we plan to share this information. You can also notify us of your desire not to have your information shared by sending us an email request at [**cs@mediaringtalk.com**](mailto:cs@mediaringtalk.com).  
In connection with alliances, partnerships or arrangements, we may also provide certain information to third parties if we have determined that the information will be used in a responsible manner by a responsible third party. For example, some of our partners may operate stores or provide services on our site, while others provide offerings developed by us for your use.  
We also use third parties to facilitate our business, including, but not limited to, sending email. In connections with these offerings and business operations, our partners and other third parties may have access to your personal information for use in connection with business activities. As we develop our business, we may buy or sell assets or business offerings. Customer, email and visitor information is generally one of the transferred business assets in these types of transaction. We may also transfer such information in the course of corporate divestitures, mergers, or any dissolution. As our customer you can notify us of your desire not to have your information shared by sending us and email request at [**cs@mediaringtalk.com**](mailto:cs@mediaringtalk.com).  
We may disclose your personal information if required to do so by law or subpoena or if we believe that such actions is necessary to (a) conform to the law or comply with legal process served on us or affiliated parties; (b) protect and defend our rights and property, our site, the users of our site, and/or our affiliated parties; (c) act under circumstances to protect the safety of users of our site, us or third parties.   
  
PROTECTION OF YOUR DETAILS  
  
When you register for our services, purchase our services, or access account details, we use a secure server. Any data you give us is encrypted using a ”Secure Socket Layer” (SSL) connection. SSL is an industry standard and is one of the best ways to ensure Internet messages are not intercepted. You should be aware, however, that older browsers cannot use SSL or might not have sufficient encryption capability. To be sure, you will need Netscape version 6.1 or Internet Explorer browsers version 5.0 or above.  
MediaRing will take appropriate organizational and technical measures to protect your personal information and the data exchanged on the Talk client application with due observance of applicable law.  
Over and above what we do to safeguard your privacy and security, there are a number of things you can do to protect yourself from Internet fraud: Choose a password you can remember but others will not guess. Change it regularly, and if you do write it down, keep it somewhere safe and secure. If your laptop or computer or mobile phone handset is lost or stolen, you should log-on to the service and change your password and security question.  
When you have finished a session on our web site, make sure that you prevent your details being seen by anyone that you do not wish to see them. So, if you have registered and logged in, remember to log off. Clear any ”cache” so there is no record of any transactions left on screen – both Netscape and Internet Explorer let you do this. We recommend you then close your browser so any history of the session is cleared. As an extra precaution, when you log-on to our website, your session on the website will terminate if you have not used the site for 10 minutes. Likewise, when using the MediaRing Talk client application on your computer or handset, remember to close the client application if you go away from your computer or handset, lest any person in the vicinity uses your account or exhausts your account balance without your permission.   
  
UPDATING YOUR DETAILS  
  
If you want to review or change any of the information that you have provided to us, such as your email address or name, you may log-in on [**www.mediaringtalk.com**](http://www.mediaringtalk.com/) at the account sign-in and update your user profile.  
  
| SECURITY OF THE INTERNET  
---  
  
**Public Forums**. Our site may contain, from time to time, public forums available to users. Please remember that any information you disclose in these areas becomes public information. You should take appropriate measures to protect your personally identifiable information.

 **Co-Branded Sites**. We sometimes enter arrangements with third parties whereby we make available our services through their web sites with a co-branded page that we host and serve. In some such cases, users may register for our service as well as that of the co-branded party. We use your PII and other general information in compliance with our Privacy Policy. Our co-branding partners have their own privacy policy, which you should review since we do not have control over their privacy policies.

 **Links to Other Web Sites**. Our website and client application may contain, from time to time, links to other web sites by virtue of ads being served. Please note that MediaRing is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such web sites or of any third party. You should review the privacy policies of such web sites when you visit them.  
  
GENERAL  
  
The Internet is not a secure medium, so be aware that communications over it are subject to third-party interception and eavesdropping. Your conversations, text messages and SMS messages when using MediaRing Talk services are not secure.  
  
YOUR CONSENT  
  
By submitting your information, you consent to the use of that information and other information we collect as set out in this Policy. MediaRing reserves the right to change the terms of this Privacy Policy for any reason. If we change our Privacy Policy, we will post the changes on this page, and may place notices on other parts of the web site so that you may become aware of the information we collect and how we use it. The revised Privacy Policy shall become effective within seven (7) days of such publishing, unless you expressly accept the revised statement earlier by clicking on the accept button. You agree that the express acceptance by you, or your continued use of our services after the notice period of thirty (30) days will signify your acceptance to the changes and to our use of your information.   
  
YOUR CONSENT  
  
MediaRing will retain your information, including, but limited to any PII for so long as is necessary to: a) comply with applicable laws and regulations or relevant orders from courts; or b) fulfill any of the purposes set forth in this Privacy Policy. "MediaRing" is a registered trademark of MediaRing Ltd in Singapore, the USA, and other countries. "MediaRing Talk" is a registered trademark of MediaRing Ltd in Singapore and the USA.   

November, 2009  

  |   |    
  |   |
